(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-28T09:43:31.459928",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
心臓に傷を負った
A scar upon my heart,
癒えない 言えない 黒い傷
an unhealed, unspoken black scar.
涙が溢れ出して止まらない
Tears overflow and won't stop—
早く止血剤をくれ！
hurry, give me a hemostat!
無意味な液体を流し込む
Pouring in meaningless liquid,
化学反応で発作が起こって
a chemical reaction triggers a seizure,
あいつの身体は重傷になって
and his body sustains severe injuries—
どうやら手遅れのようだ…
looks like it's too late...
亡命している、している、している
Living in exile, in exile, in exile,
亡命している、している、生命を蹂躙している
in exile, trampling over life itself.
幸福に浸って帰らぬ医療廃棄物となった
Becoming medical waste lost in pure bliss.
注射器にキスをした
I kissed the syringe.
冥界は冷静に笑った
The underworld laughed calmly.
p.h.って胃酸を沢山吐いていて
With p.h., I'm vomiting loads of stomach acid,
体内は空
and my body is completely empty.
高尚な志に支配された
Dominated by noble aspirations,
拙い拙い自慰行為
a clumsy, clumsy act of masturbation.
所谓ハッピーエンドじゃないから実世界では生きていけない
It's not a happy ending, so I can't survive in the real world.
おびえらって 脳みそともども食れてやる
Trembling in fear, I'll eat up your brain right along with you.
悪い自己意識の塊を持って あなたの血肉になれるなら
Taking this mass of wicked self-awareness, if it can become your flesh and blood—
溶解している 溶解している
It's dissolving, it's dissolving...
平衡は相殺している 相殺している
Equilibrium is offsetting, offsetting...
映画と映画が混ざり合って自己解離定数を満たした
Movies and movies mixed together, satisfying the self-dissociation constant.
ちゅちゅちゅちゅちゅ セイトハハハハハ ハグを頂戴
Chu-chu-chu-chu-chu, Saint, ha-ha-ha-ha-ha, give me a hug!
めめめめめ 冥界で生命はちぎりたべ
Me-me-me-me-me, tearing and eating life in the underworld,
ぺぺぺぺぺ よだれを綺麗に拭いている
Pe-pe-pe-pe-pe, wiping away the drool neatly.
たたたたた 体内を喰う
Ta-ta-ta-ta-ta, devouring inside the body.
ちゅちゅちゅちゅちゅ 注射器キキキキキ キッスを頂戴
Chu-chu-chu-chu-chu, syringe, ki-ki-ki-ki-ki, give me a kiss!
めめめめめ 冥界は冷静に笑った
Me-me-me-me-me, the underworld laughed calmly.
ぺぺぺぺぺ 胃酸を沢山吐いている
Pe-pe-pe-pe-pe, spewing out lots of stomach acid.
たたたたた 体内は空
Ta-ta-ta-ta-ta, the inside is empty.
絶望は幸福になって
Despair turns into happiness,
空想は実在になって
fantasy becomes reality,
錆び切った感覚は中和している
and rusted senses are being neutralized.
生活は残骸になって
Life becomes wreckage,
正常は官房になって腐り尽くした
normality rots away entirely,
吐瀉物で乾杯をした
and we toasted with vomit.
ちょっと 休憩 よいしょ
Whew... Just a little break. Heave-ho.
はいということで皆さんどうもこんばんは ホロライブゲーマーズの猫又おかゆです
Right, so everyone, good evening! I'm Nekomata Okayu from Hololive Gamers.
今日は私の誕生日なんだけど ちょっと疲れたんでね横に鳴らしてください
Today is my birthday, but since I got a little tired, I'm gonna lie down here for a bit.
えっと あ、そうそう 今日に向けて僕めっちゃねダンスとか練習してきて 頑張って 頑張って覚えてきたからみんなにめっちゃ楽しみにしててほしいんだよね
Um, oh right! I practiced dancing really hard for today, so I hope everyone looks forward to it.
でも この後もめっちゃ頑張るけど ちょっと1回休憩させて
But I'll keep doing my best after this too, so just let me take a quick break first!
あ、でもね 今日は配信最後まで見ててほしいんだよね
Oh, but you know, I want you guys to watch the stream all the way to the end today.
僕の誕生日をお祝いしてほしいていうのもあるけど さの最後のほうでみんなが喜ぶような告知があったりとかするからね
Of course to celebrate my birthday, but also because towards the end, there'll be happy announcements!
まあ僕ね 最近作詞勉強とかしてて ま、何がとは言わないけど、何がとは言わないけど 作詞勉強してたんだよね
Lately I've been studying lyric writing... well, I won't say what kind, but I have been!
で、今一番最初に歌ったpHていう曲は 僕がもうすっごく大好きで 歌ってみたの動画もね出したりとかしてるんだけど
The song "p.h." I sang right at the beginning is one I just love so much, and I've even released a cover video of it...
踊りもすごく大好きだったから 踊ってみたいなって思っててたんで ちょっとその夢を叶えちゃいました
and I loved the dance too, so I thought I'd love to dance to it, and made that dream come true!
ちょっと疲れたけど、まあ次、あの、あ、ゲストもねいっぱい来てくださってるんで
I got a little tired, but next, lots of guests have come to join us, so...
ゲストのみんなのとこに行こうと思います じゃあみんな さろばー
I think I'll go check on everyone. Alright everyone, see you later—!
触れてみたい秘密と壊してみたい夜の中で
In a night where I want to touch secrets and break them apart,
間違いだらけの遊びしようよ
let's play a game full of mistakes.
シニカルナイトプラン 作詞・作曲：Ayase
[Song: Cynical Night Plan | Lyrics & Music: Ayase]
別に意味とか無いけどさ 眠い目をこする
There's no particular meaning, but I rub my sleepy eyes.
あれ？待ち合わせは何時だっけ
Huh? What time was our meeting supposed to be?
「君はまだ壁違いでる」 また間違えてる それで？貴方は誰なの
"You're still getting it wrong again." So, who are you anyway?
こうして居たい居たいのはお互い様 目が合う度に
The reason we want to stay like this is mutual; every time our eyes meet,
名前は呼ばないで どうやったって見たいの隠さないから
don't call me by my name. No matter what, I want to see it, so I won't hide it.
私のフリした私でよければどうぞ
If you're fine with me pretending to be me, go right ahead.
ぶっさぐ目に落ちる景色の様に
Like scenery dropping into pierced eyes,
霞む私は誰のもでもないのバイビ
the hazy me belongs to no one, bye-bye.
ソフィニカルからかわないでね 私だけにみせて 歪な夜をどうぞ
Sophinical, don't tease me. Show it only to me—a distorted night, go on.
ほら本当うるさったやいやや
Look, you're really being so noisy, ya-ya-ya!
何処かの誰かと赤の信号渡りよ いいでしょ？だめって分るでしょ？
Crossing a red light with someone somewhere—isn't it fine? You know you shouldn't, right?
青に染まってたんだつまんないやいやや
Dyed in blue, how boring, ya-ya-ya.
何処かの誰かと赤の信号渡りよ いいでしょ？だめって分るでしょ？
Crossing a red light with someone somewhere—isn't it fine? You know you shouldn't, right?
ダメって分かるでしょ？青に染まってたんだし つまんないや
You know it's a no-go, right? It was dyed in blue... how boring.
ドクドク流れるテロップ 交わす言葉に絡めるシロップ
The text scrolls with a thumping beat, syrup entangling our exchanged words.
早くドキドキさせてよほら 腐敗する誰かと私のエゴ
Hurry and make my heart race, hey—robbing ego of someone decaying alongside mine.
たまんないわ いつものように 騙し騙され重なる凶器 揺れるように 無情に あとはただ堕ちるだけ
I can't get enough, as usual, deceiving and deceived, overlapping weapons swaying ruthlessly, leaving only to fall.
触れてみたい秘密と 壊してみたい夜の中で
In the night where I want to touch secrets and break them,
間違いを繰り返して
repeating mistakes...
触れてみたい秘密を 壊して知る夜の味を
Touching the secret I want to touch, breaking it to know the taste of night,
戻れないはじめましてをどうぞ
welcome to the point of no return.
塞ぐ目に落ちる景色のように 霞む私は
Like scenery falling before blocked eyes, my hazy self
誰のもでもないの
belongs to no one.
buy me so feeling からかわないで
Buy me, so feeling, don't tease me,
私だけに見せて 歪な夜をどうぞ
show only to me this distorted night, please.
塞ぐ目に落ちる景色のように 霞む私は 誰のもでもないの
Like scenery falling before blocked eyes, my hazy self belongs to no one.
buy me so feeling からかわないで 私だけに見せて 秘密の夜をどうぞ
Buy me, so feeling, don't tease me, show only to me this secret night, please.
はあ！ ああ！ はあ！
Haah! Aaah! Haah!
とわ！おかゆ！おめでとう！ありがとう！
Towa! Okayu! Happy birthday! Thank you!
とわが歌ってるから気付かなかったけど、そんなテンション高かったら…
Towa was singing so I didn't notice, but if your excitement was that high...
いや、歌うときはちょっとカッコつけてるだけだもん。
Well, when I sing, I just try to look a bit cool.
もう本当におめでとうの気持ちなんだけど、もうこういうことじゃん。いや嬉しいじゃん。
But really, it's all feelings of congratulations, you know, isn't it great? I'm so happy.
嬉しい。今めちゃめちゃ嬉しかったよ。
I'm happy. I was super happy just now.
いやでもさ、とわの誕生日にね、出させてもらっててだから…今日ね、僕の誕生日にとわが祝いに来てくれたら嬉しいなって思ってたんだよね。
But you know, since I got to appear on Towa's birthday, I was hoping Towa would come celebrate my birthday too today.
いや、でもさ、とわ、今回違うなと思ったのが、とわの生誕祭とか、記念配信はさ、二人で歌うことなかったじゃん。
Yeah, but you know, what felt different this time, Towa, was that for your birthday or anniversary streams, we never sang as a duo, right?
3人とか…そうそう、二人で歌ったのは、あの家でゲラゲラ…
Three people... right, right, the only time we sang as a duo was laughing hysterically at the house...
僕さ、今日自分の誕生日のライブにトワを呼ぶことに1つ心配があって。トワと歌うと笑っちゃうから、その歌い切れるかなっていう心配があったんだけど…
Today for my birthday live, I had one worry about inviting Towa. Since I laugh when singing with Towa, I was worried if I'd be able to finish singing...
でも歌ってるトワはやっぱりかっこいいし、踊ってるトワもかっこいいから、今日は笑わずに完走できたよね。
But Towa singing is so cool, and Towa dancing is cool too, so we made it through without laughing today, right?
いやでさ、あの、まあ確かに歌はちゃんと歌ったけど、その前めっちゃゲラゲラ笑ってたじゃん。はいやりましょうの前。
Well, we sang properly, but before that, we were laughing hysterically, right? Right before "Okay, let's do it."
いやでもさ、今日トワ気づいてたかわかんないけど、僕トワの歌い方を今日ちょっと寄せて歌ってみたんだけど気づいた？
But you know, I don't know if Towa noticed today, but I tried singing a bit closer to Towa's singing style today, did you notice?
いや、かっこよかったわ！本当に！めちゃくちゃよかったよ！
Yeah, it was cool! Really! It was super good!
いやだからやっぱり歌ったわ、そうよ！え？何？歌ってみた…そう…出そう出そうって言ってまだ出してないから…
That's why I sang, that's right! Eh? What? I tried singing... right... we said we'd release it, but we haven't released it yet...
いやじゃあ出そうよ、今年はさ！じゃあ出そう！じゃあみなさん出します！
Well then let's release it this year! Then let's release it! Then everyone, we're releasing it!
じゃあ…えっと…えっと…ありがとうございました！ありがとうございましたー！
Well then... um... um... Thank you very much! Thank you very much!
存在証明 愛だって愛だって吐いたって
Proof of existence—even if I spit out "it's love, it's love,"
鳴呼 寝転んずゴロンして嫌嫌 プリティプリティダイエットDAY
ah, rolling around lazily, hating it, pretty pretty diet day.
曖昧 一回 楽に 曖昧 二回 楽に
Ambiguous once for ease, ambiguous twice for ease,
病み悪化してんだって 愛だ恋だなんだってな
sickness getting worse they say—love, romance, and all that.
生命線は 愛だって愛だって嘆いたって
Even if the lifeline laments "it's love, it's love,"
ああ でもない こうでもないな 寂しい寂しいナンセンスDAY
ah, it's neither this nor that, a lonely, lonely nonsense day.
いっそ密会 ラフに 節操無い解 ： LOVE ME
Rather, a casual secret meeting with indiscriminate answers: LOVE ME.
溺れ奴隷 踊れ踊れ 亡霊だ
Drowning slaves, dance, dance, you're ghosts.
なにもない なにもない 私なにもない
There's nothing, nothing, I have nothing.
変われない 変われない 私変われない
I can't change, can't change, I can't change.
分からない 分からない 分かる分からない
I don't know, don't know, I get it, I don't get it.
はい 目元以外は隠して
Yes, hide everything except your eyes.
ダ・ダ・ダ・ダ・ダーリン、ダリ・ダリ・ダリ・ファニー
Da-da-da-da-darling, dari-dari-dari-funny,
はい 冴えない愛情論でおねだり
begging with a dull theory of love.
ダダダダ　ダーリン　汚い＆汚い
Da-da-da-da, darling, dirty & dirty
会いたい衝動　埋めてよ　ダダダーリン
Fill up the rushing impulse, da-da-darling
ナナナナナナナナナナナナナナナ
Na, na, na, na, na, na, na...
無い無い純情　感情が行ったり来たり
Pure innocence is going back and forth
ナナナナナナナナナナナナナナナ
Na, na, na, na, na, na, na...
無い無い純情　感傷で　ダダダーリン　チュッ
Pure innocence and a wounded heart, da-da-darling, chu!
ダダダダ　ダーリン　愛だけ描いて
Da-da-da-da, darling, I'll paint it with love
食い意地　食い意地　ダイエットDAY
Gluttony, gluttony, dieting day
もう精一杯で詰み　ボロ世界で無理
Giving it my absolute all, packed tight
闇暴き捨てたって　承認承認世界だ
Exposing the darkness, approved, approved, perfectly
なにもない　なにもない　私なにもない
Nothing, nothing, I have nothing at all
はしたない　はしたない　私したない
I won't be improper, I won't, I won't, I won't!
わからない　わからない　「わかる」わからない
I don't understand, I don't... "I get it," I don't understand
はい　自撮りは全部加工して　ダッパッパッパ
Right, hiding all my selfies except for my face!
ダダダダ　ダーリン(笑)FUNNY
Da-da-da-da, darling, funny!
はい　絶えない愛情論で冷めたり
Sure, getting cold with unchanging theories of love
ダダダダ　ダーリン無理　ダーリン
Da-da-da-da, darling, impossible, darling!
会いたい衝動　埋めてよ　ダダダーリン
Fill up the rushing impulse, da-da-darling
踊れ　踊れ　叫べ　叫べ　踊れ　踊れ　ルラパパパ
Dance, dance, shout, shout, dance, ru-ra-pa-pa
踊れ　踊れ　唄え　唄え　踊れ　踊れ　ルラパパパ
Dance, dance, sing, sing, dance, ru-ra-pa-pa
はい　素顔は全部無くして　ダッパッパッパ
Yes, hiding all my bare faces completely away!
ダダダダ　ダーリン(笑)FUNNY
Da-da-da-da, darling, funny!
どうしようもない感情論に喋ったり
Nattering on about hopelessly silly emotions
ダダダダ　ダーリン　汚い＆汚い
Da-da-da-da, darling, dirty & dirty
会いたい衝動　埋めてよ　ダダダーリン
Fill up the rushing impulse, da-da-darling
ナナナナナナナナナナナナナナナ
Na, na, na, na, na, na, na...
無い無い反応　返答を　期待したり
Hoping for no reaction or replies, wanting it down below
ナナナナナナナナナナナナナナナ
Na, na, na, na, na, na, na...
無い無い妄想　感傷で　ダダダーリン
With absurd delusions and sentimental wounds, da-da-darling
お誕生日おめでとうございます！
Happy birthday! Congratulations!
ありがとうございます！二人とも来てくれてありがとうございます！
Thank you so much! Thank you both so much for coming!
ありがとうございます！ありがとうございます！めっちゃ嬉しいよー！
Thank you so much, thank you so much! I'm so happy!
どうしてこの3人で歌おうって思ってくださったんですか？
So, why did you decide to sing with these three?
僕はね、かなたんとうみちゃん歌声がめっちゃ好きで！
Well, I really love Kanata's and Marine's singing voices!
で、二人も僕の歌好きって言ってくれてるの知ってたからさ！
And you two always said you liked my singing too!
それにあやかってみんなで3人で歌わせてもらっちゃおうからと思って！いや、嬉しいです！
So I thought, why not ask to sing together as three? Yay!
嬉しい！
So happy!
え、そんな割って入るほどの仲じゃ…
Wait, isn't that too close?
え、割って入るようなほど、そんなつながり…繋がってないよ、別に！
Wait, we're not that close!
そんな尊い感じのアレじゃないんです！
It's not like it's some profound thing!
割れなくても割れてます、大丈夫！
Well, even if we aren't, we are!
いやいやいやいや、いやいや、むしろね！
No, no, no, no, no, no!
むしろね、かなおかゆの間に挟まる…
Rather, we're the Kanata-Marine sandwich!
なんで終わらせるんだよ！
Wait, why are you ending it?!
今からマリおかゆの時代だよ！マリおか！
Now begins the era of "Mari-Okayu"!
いや、おかゆにはね…マリすべり…すべってる！
Wait, Marine-chan, you're slipping!
なんでタイミング…まりまりなんだよ！
Wait, what kind of timing is that?!
まあまあまあ、今日はね、僕の誕生日に免じて3人で仲良くしようよ！
Well, today we should put aside our differences and be friendly for my birthday!
あ、確かに！そう言うなら！仲良くして、争わないで！
If that's the case, let's get along without fighting!
終電はもうないよ
With the last train already gone,
これからどうしようかなんて
wondering what we should do from here,
迷い込んだみたい二人で
the two of us got lost in thought.
終点なんてないの
There's no such thing as a final stop,
明日のことなんてほら今は考えないでよね
so let's not think about tomorrow for now.
夜撫でるメノウ　作詞・作曲 : Ayase
Yorunaderu Menou / Ayase
終電はもうないよ
The last train is already gone,
これからどうしようかなんて
wondering what we should do from here.
迷い込みたいような二人で
The two of us, wanting to lose ourselves—
終点なんかないの
there's no such thing as a last stop.
明日のことなんてほら
What will happen tomorrow, hey—
今は考えないでね
let's not think about that now.
いつもと同じペースで歩く
Walking at the same pace as always,
街に二人の影映す
two silhouettes are cast on the streets.
君に届けとこの愛を
The love I sent to you
言葉にのせる毎日を
in the form of words every day—
美しく思えないと
if you can't think of it as beautiful,
いつかは消えてしまうの
then it'll disappear someday.
これで終わりだなんて
It's a curious feeling,
不思議な気持ちになるけど
that this is how it ends,
元気でね
but stay well.
いつもと違うテンポで笑う
Laughing to a different beat than usual,
君は今何を考えているのか
what are you thinking about now?
わざとらしく萎れた空気
In this unnatural, gloomy atmosphere,
少し息が震える
my breath trembles a little.
今まで話したこと
All the things we talked about up till now,
全て覚えてはいないけれど
I can't say I remember them all, but
ありがとうの言葉とごめんねと
the words "thank you" and "sorry"—
上手に伝えられなかったから
I couldn't convey them well, so
こんな結末を迎えたのなら
is that why we've arrived at this ending?
ごめんね、遅すぎたね
If so, to say "sorry" is too late, right?
君に届けとこの愛を
The love I sent to you
言葉にのせる毎日を
in the form of words every day—
息苦しく思えちゃうほど
when was it that I started feeling
いつから変わってしまったの？
it had started getting harder to breathe?
これで終わりだなんて
I still can't believe
まだ信じられないけれど
that this is how it ends,
元気でね
but stay well.
終電前のホーム
On the platform before the last train,
言葉が出てこないな
the words aren't coming at all.
ここからはもう一人で
From here on out, I'll be alone—
出逢えなければなんてそんなの思っていないよ
I'm not thinking "if only we hadn't crossed paths."
だから笑って、笑ってよね
So smile and be happy, alright.
君に届けとこの愛を
The love I sent to you
言葉にのせる毎日を
in the form of words every day—
美しく思えないと
if you can't think of it as beautiful,
いつかは消えてしまうの
then it'll disappear someday.
これで終わりだなんて
It's a curious feeling,
不思議な気持ちになるけど
that this is how it ends,
元気でね
but stay well.
君に貰ったこの愛も
This love I received from you
この手で触れた毎日も
and the days that were touched by these hands—
あんまりにも美しいから
they were too beautiful, so
涙が溢れてしまうよ
the tears are overflowing.
これで終わりだねって
So this is how it ends, huh—
最後の言葉になるけど
these are my last words to you,
ありがとうね
but thank you.
わあー！
Waaah!
あー、よかったー！
Ah, I'm so glad!
きてくれてありがとう！
Thank you for coming!
お誕生日おめでとう！
Happy birthday!
ありがとう、あくあ！
Thank you, Aqua!
いや、おかゆまさか私の誕生日に呼んでくれるなんて
I never thought you'd invite me to your birthday, Okayu!
まあ、あくあもね、よくあくあのライブに私のこと呼んでくれるからさ、今日は、そう、私はあくあのこと呼びたいなと思って呼ばせてもらったんだよね。
Well, Aqua often invites me to her concerts, so today, I wanted to invite Aqua, so that's why I asked you to join.
そんなにデュエットしたかったの？おかゆ。えっ、私のこと好きじゃん、えっ！
Did you want to duet with me that much, Okayu? Eh, you must really like me, eh!
なんだ？
What?
ちょっと待って、それ私が言うやつだから。あくあ、私のこと好き！い、い…
Wait a second, that's my line. Aqua, you like me! I, i...
そう、そんなんじゃないよ、そんなんじゃない…もっと可愛いよ。もっと可愛い。
Yeah, it's not like that, not like that... You're cuter. Much cuter.
そっか。ま、でも今日はね、あくあ…あくあに最初教えてもらった「夜撫でるメノウ」を今日は二人で歌えてすごい嬉しかったよ。
I see. Well, but today, I was so happy we could sing "Yoru Naderu Menou", which Aqua first taught me, together today.
いや、本当にね、この曲やっぱね、私たちの愛のラブソング。
Yeah, truly, this song is like our love song.
え、なんか流しそうめんしたくなった曲じゃなかった？
Eh, wasn't it a song that made you want to do somen noodle flowing?
流しそうめんはしたくなるね、この曲なんだから。
You'd definitely want to do somen flowing with this song, after all.
しんみりしちゃったよ一緒に歌ってて
We got all emotional singing together.
ねえ！すごい！おかゆと歌えてよかったよ本当に入り…ありがとう
Right! It's amazing! I'm so glad I could sing with Okayu, really... Thank you.
じゃあさ、僕がアクアのライブに出させてもらってる時いつもね、僕がアクアを置いてきぼりで帰るっていうのがお約束になってるけど
So, whenever I appear in Aqua's live, it's usually a promise that I leave Aqua behind and go home, but
今日は…（お約束？うん）そう、今日はアクアが帰ってもいい日にするよ。
Today is... (A promise? Yeah) Right, today will be the day Aqua is allowed to go home.
いや、帰らないよ私えっ？
No, I'm not going home. Huh?
えっ今天是もうここの現場に居続ける気で来た。えっ？
Eh, today I came here with the intention of staying at this venue forever. Eh?
そしたらおかゆとずっといられるわけんでしょ？えっ おかゆいつも帰っちゃうから。
That way I can stay with Okayu forever, right? Eh, because Okayu always goes home.
じゃあしょうがない、今日も僕が帰りますか。
Well then, can't be helped. I guess I'll go home today too.
ちょっと！おかゆ！やだね！ここに居ず、やだ！やだ！やだ！私ずっとここにいるからね！いるからね！いるからね！ここ！いや！やだ！やだ！
Wait! Okayu! No way! Staying here— no! No! No! I'm gonna stay right here! I'm staying! I'm staying! Right here! No! No! No!
「あたし計算はイマイチ 引き算ばっかり」
"My calculations are second-rate, just subtractions."
「自然数xを求めよとかそういうのわかんない」
"I don't get stuff like 'find the natural number x'."
デュワ デュワ デュワ デュワ デュワ デュワ
Doo-wop doo-wop doo-wop doo-wop doo-wop doo-wop
ーと炭酸の割合だけは完璧だけれど
Only the ratio of sugar and carbonation is perfect, but
ココロとカラダ切り離してる やればできてしまうので
Mind and body are detached, because I can do it if I try.
まともな人って難しいのね ふりするのは簡単だけれど
Being a decent person is hard, even if acting like one is easy.
二人の声もとぎれとぎれ 夜が長すぎたのは誰のため？
Our voices are intermittent too—for whose sake was the night so long?
さよなら涙 はじめまして涙 切り出したなら戻れない
Goodbye tears, nice to meet you tears. Once you start, you can't go back.
「あたし国語もイマイチ 鉛筆ころがし」
"My Japanese is second-rate too, just rolling a pencil."
「筆者の心境として適切なものを選びなさい」「つっか宿題 終わone-night」
"Choose the appropriate option for the author's mood." "Stuck on homework, finishing in one night."
デュラ デュラ デュラ デュラ デュラ デュラ
Dura dura dura dura dura dura
trapハマっちゃうよ私みたいな分かりやすい女にしなよ
You'll fall into a trap, make it an easy-to-understand girl like me!
フロアに喧騒ぶっちらけようよく聞こえない聞こえないけどまぁいっか
Let's scatter the commotion across the floor. I can't hear well, can't hear well, but oh well!
酔っぱらっちゃうしょうがない誰も傷つかないちょっとくらいショットグラス空けて
Getting drunk can't be helped, nobody gets hurt. Emptying a shot glass or two,
それじゃダメだって誰かに叱ってほしい なぐさめるなら後にして
I want someone to scold me that that's no good. If you're going to comfort me, do it later!
さよなら涙 はじめまして涙 振り出しまでは戻れない
Goodbye tears, nice to meet you tears. You can't go back to square one.
よくいる女ね愛しいね なにがバカにしないで早くして
Such a common woman, how lovely. What? Don't treat me like a fool, hurry up!
救われたいよねなんか文句あんのかよ 遊びじゃねえんだよあとにして
You want to be saved, do you have any complaints? It's not a game, do it later!
優しさなんかどうでもいい
Kindness or whatever can be however it wants.
流されるなら今にして
If you're going to get swept away, do it now!
おい！おかゆ！おめでとう！
Hey! Okayu! Congratulations!
えー！スバちゃん！祝いに来てくれたの？
Eh! Subaru-chan! Did you come to celebrate?
祝いに来てくれたって何でこんだけ踊っといて、踊って歌っといて、祝いに来たよおめでとう！
What do you mean "did I come to celebrate", after dancing and singing all this much, I came to celebrate, congrats!
ありがとう！そう、スバちゃんがね僕の好きな歌を覚えて、踊りまで覚えてきてくれたんだよ。
Thank you! That's right, Subaru-chan remembered my favorite song, and even learned the dance for it.
うらなりからこう行こう？
Should we go like...
そうそうそう！
So yeah!
なんか僕、スバルちゃんのカッコいい歌声聴いてみたいなと思って、
So I wanted to hear Subaru's cool singing voice,
そう、一緒にね歌いたかったんだよ。
and wanted to sing together!
だってもう、なんだったら1回、その、
I mean, if we were going to do it,
もうマジで、わかん、正解わかんなすぎて、
I couldn't figure out the right way to do it,
ど深夜に歌録って、
so I recorded it late at night,
こんな感じで歌う感じでいいの？って送って、感修してもらったから。
and sent it to you asking, "Is this the right vibe?"
いやでもスバルちゃんは、なんかその不安がってる割にはちゃん歌ってるから、
Yeah, but Subaru, you sound pretty good even though you're nervous,
逆にコメントに困るよね。
so it's almost awkward for comments.
だってちゃんと歌わないといけないだろ！
Well, of course I have to sing properly!
大事な私の誕生日だもん！
It's my birthday, you know!
自分で言うなよ！
Say it yourself!
自分で言うなよ、お前！
Say it yourself, you idiot!
言わせてくれよ、おかゆ！
At least let me say it, Okayu!
いいよ言ってくれても。
Even if you say something nice...
いやいや、もう大丈夫です、ありがとうございました。
No, no, I'm totally fine. Thank you.
なんでよ！えー、私の誕生日にもスバルちゃんは出てきてくれないの？
What's that? Eh, you couldn't even show up for my birthday?
いや、出れないだろ。別に、いや、いつも出れてるだろ、むしろ。
Well, I couldn't. Besides, I always show up anyway.
あ、そうなんだ。
Oh, is that right?
心当たりないんかい！
You don't care at all!
そんなにも愛情かけてたのに、何にも感じてくれてないじゃん！
Even though I showed you so much affection, you didn't care at all!
いや、もっとスバルちゃんが出れたら、あの
No, I thought if you showed up,
「スバルもー！」みたいな感じになるのかと思ってたからさ。
it'd be like "Super Subaru!" or something, so...
いや、ならねぇわ、ごめん！
Well, I can't do that, sorry!
ならねぇのか。ま、でもね、スバルちゃん、今日は
Can you? Well, anyway, Subaru-chan,
あの、僕の誕生日に、お祝いに来てくれて、ありがとう。
thanks for coming to celebrate my birthday.
うわ！うわ、恥ずかし！
Geez, how emotional!
なんか、胸に来た。今なんか、
I'm actually really happy,
切なさと嬉しさが同時に来た。
though sadness and happiness hit me at the same time.
じゃあ最後にね、ちょっとみんなにもね、最大級のね、
So lastly, let's strike our absolute best...
可愛いポーズか、なんかいい感じのおかゆのポーズしてよ。
cute pose, or some cool Okayu pose!
わかった。
Got it.
行くよ。
Here I go.
はい。
Okay.
じゃあ。
Then...
ダブりおかゆ！
Double Okayu!
で、さん、はい、おめでとう！
And then, three...
おい！
Hey!
これじゃ栗逃げじゃなくて雌逃げじゃねえか！
That's not chestnut-eating, that's bitch-running!
それ言いたいだけやん！
You just wanted to say that!
G・R・D・O・U・B・L・E・N・L・E・A・V・E・S
G-R-D-O-U-B-L-E-N-L-E-A-V-E-S
It's so easy! Happy-go-lucky!
We are the world! We did it!
ヒュー！ヒュー！オス！オス！
Whoo! Ossu!
やった！やった！
Yatta! Yatta!
社長就任
President!
葉っぱ一枚あればいい
Long as we've one leaf on, we're doin' fine!
生きているからラッキーだ
We're lucky just 'cause we're alive!
やった！やった！当選確実
Yatta! Yatta! Confirmed for the prize!
やった！やった！日本代表
Yatta! Yatta! Representing Japan!
やんなるくらい健康だ
We're so healthy, it just makes ya sick!
Everybody say YATTA!
ニッポン急々（でも）
Japan's got crises! (But)
明日はWonderful
Tomorrow's wonderful!
グー！グー！パス！パス！
Snore! Snore! Pass! Pass!
「おはよー！」
Good morning!
やった！やった！九時間睡眠
Yatta! Yatta! Got nine hours of sleep!
やった！やった！寝起きでジャンプ
Yatta! Yatta! Woke up and jumped outta bed!
どんな良いことあるだろう
What kinda great things might await us now?
生きいていたからラッキーだ
We're lucky just 'cause we're alive!
やった！やった！君が変われば
Yatta! Yatta! If there's a change in you,
世界も変わる
then the whole world will change too!
まっすぐ立ったら気持ちいー！
Just stand up straight because it feels great!
お水飲んだら、うめー！
I drink water that's tasty!
フー！フー！
Whoo! Whoo!
オス！オス！
Ossu! Ossu!
フー！フー！
Whoo! Whoo!
オス！オス！
Ossu! Ossu!
やった！日様に当たったらあったけー！
Yatta! I get in the sun and feel toasty!
やった！腹から笑ったらおもしれー！
Yatta! Having a belly laugh's fun!
やった！犬飼ってみたら可愛い！
Yatta! Try keeping dogs--they're cute!
It's so easy! Happy-go-lucky!
We are the world! We did it!
ヒュー！オス！
Whoo! Ossu!
2度と会えなくたっていい
It's okay if we never meet again.
君がいたからラッキーだ
I'm lucky you were here just for a while!
不景気、政治不信
We've got recession, government in no faith...
葉っぱ最高だ
Leaves are the best!
みんな居るから楽しい！
It's fun because everyone is here!
やった！やった！
Yatta! Yatta!
大学合格
Got into college!
やった！やった！
Yatta! Yatta!
ムービースター
Movie star!
葉っぱ一枚なればいい
Long as we've one leaf on, we're fine
みんな一緒だ HAPPYだ
We're all together, happy!
やった！やった！
Yatta! Yatta!
息を吸える
Can breathe in!
やった！やった！
Yatta! Yatta!
息を吐ける
Can breathe out!
やんなるぐらい健康だ
So healthy it makes ya sick!
everybody say やったー！
Everybody say yatta!
G! R!
ダブルe!
double-e!
N!
leaves!!
G! R!
e e!
N!
leaves!!
バイキュー！
Bye-q!
はーい、ということで！
So anyway,
ゲーマーズ！
Gamers!
ゲーマーズ揃うの久しぶりでございます。
It's been a while since all four Gamers got together.
本当に本当に揃うの久しぶりでございます。
Really, really been a long time.
前回あったのは多分白上のお誕生日ですかね？
The last time was Fubuki's birthday, right?
確かに！
True!
記念日しかさ、集まらないよ。そう記念日しかさ！
We only get together on anniversaries!
それを連れてどうなんだ！
How's that going?!
いやいやでもありがとうございます今日は。
No, no, but thank you for today.
いやおめでとう！おかゆお誕生日おめでとう！
Yeah, congratulations! Happy birthday, Okayu!
頭に葉っぱをつけてね！そう葉っぱつけておじゃましますけども。
Visiting with leaves on our heads!
やっぱゲーマーズといえば、ちょっとね全力でおふざけをする
As Gamers, we go all out messing around,
チームじゃないですか、我々は。
aren't we? We are.
確かに！
True!
まあね集まらないけどね。
Well, we don't gather much though.
まあまあまあでもね、それはいいことですよ。
Well, well, but that's a good thing.
まあ自由度は高いね。
Our freedom level is high.
そうですね、我々ね。
That's true, us.
で選ばれたのがこちらの葉っぱ隊の！
And what was chosen is this Leaf Corps!
そう、もともとゲーマーズで葉っぱ隊の「YATTA!」を踊って歌いたかったんだよ。
We wanted to sing "YATTA!" as Gamers.
そうなんだ！
Is that so!
そうなんだ、よかったね。
That's right, I'm glad.
そう、自分の誕生日にこの夢が叶ってすごく嬉しいんだよ。
I'm so happy this dream came true.
ありがとうみんな！頭に葉っぱをつけてね。
Thank you everyone! With leaves on.
なんかさ、やったのさ歌詞の中でさ、「みんな何が好き？」みたいなさ。
In the lyrics, it asks what everyone likes.
白上は何が好き？「ベッドの上！」
Fubuki, what do you like? "On the bed!"
そこがね、楽しかったな。
That part was fun.
うちは「息が滑る、息が滑る」だね。
For me, it's "breath slips".
当たり前だけだ！当たり前じゃないね。
That's obvious! Well, not really.
どこだ、どこのは？
Where is it?
やっぱり「日本、キュウキュウから」ベッドが好きだね。
I love the bed from "Japan, Kyu-kyu".
なるほどね！おかゆは？
I see! What about Okayu?
僕はやっぱり水飲んだらね。
For me, drinking water.
確かに、いいよね。
True, that's nice.
いや、やったよ。本当に楽しかったよ。この4人で歌えてよかったね。
I'm glad we could sing with these four.
いや、本当にこうやって集まることってね。
Seriously, gathering like this...
ゲームもしよう、ゲームも、コラボもしよう！ゲーマーズですからね。
Let's collaborate! Because we're Gamers.
みんなさ、この4人で歌った感想は、なんか、ちょっと、簡単に？
Everyone, impressions of singing briefly?
いやでも、やっぱりこれはめちゃくちゃ聞いてると元気がでるから。
Listening to this really gives you energy.
そっか。やっぱね、こう今聞いてくれてるみんなも、リスナー諸君もね、疲れたらまたこのゲーマーズの「やった」を聴きに来てほしいなって思うよ。
I hope listeners will come back when tired.
めちゃいいコメントをいただきました！ありがとう！
That's a great comment! Thank you!
なんかさ、やっぱさ、おかゆってさ、歌聴いてて思ったけどさ、歌うまいよね。
Okayu is really good at singing.
確かに、うまいうまい！あれ？なんか葉っぱが大きくなってる！
True! Huh? The leaf is getting bigger!
おかゆかわいい！歌うまいよ！
Okayu is cute! You sing so well!
やばいやばい！でかいよ！でかくなっちゃった！キモいちょっとキモい。
It's huge! Creepy, a bit creepy.
おかゆ大好き！
I love Okayu!
拝啓 僕の願いよ 未来よ
Dear my wishes, my futures,
絶え間無い 後悔よ
my endless regrets,
体感八度
sensational 8 degrees...
拝啓 僕の願いよ 未来よ 絶え間無い後悔よ
Dear me, my wish, my future, my endless regrets...
体感八度五分の夢は やがて散ってしまった
The 8.5-degree sensory dream eventually scattered away.
再啓 君の想いは 憂いは 巡る感情論は
Re: Greetings, your thoughts and sorrows, your recurring sentimentalism...
半径八十五分の世界に囚われた侭
Trapped inside a world with a radius of 85 centimeters.
本音を挿し躙られた今日を
Today, my true feelings were trampled upon,
溢れた一切に
pouring into everything—
薪を焼べて 風に乗せて
I'll burn firewood, let it ride the wind,
錆びた空を彩る
and color the rusted sky.
燻んだ日々を丁寧に
Carefully decorating these gloomy days,
飾った花は直ぐに枯れてく
the flowers wither away so fast.
愚鈍な僕は夢から覚めて
Foolish me, waking up from the dream,
綴った意味も無い無い無いな
with no meaning left at all...
君が僕にくれた 声も 色も
The voice, the colors, and the unwavering affection
揺るぎない愛情も
that you gave to me—
二人きりの空に光った星も とうに散ってしまった
and the stars shining in our lonely sky have long since scattered.
難儀の末のモノクロの疲弊に
Amidst the monochromatic exhaustion after much hardship,
季節は色褪せて 熱を帯びて
the seasons fade in color, taking on heat,
鈍く澱んで擦れた街に零る
spilling into the dull, sluggish, and frayed town.
不毛な日々を丁寧に
Carefully tending to barren days,
綴った紙に花を描いた
I drew flowers on the woven paper.
不遇な僕らは夢に敗れて
Unfortunate, defeated by our dreams,
誓った筈も無かった事にした
we pretended the vows we made never happened.
木漏れ日の中に 柔らかく咲いた花は
The flowers blooming softly in the sunbeams
雲の上で 違う星で 夢の先で揺れてる
sway above the clouds, on a different star, beyond the dream.
燻んだ日々を丁寧に
Carefully decorating these gloomy days,
飾った花は直ぐに枯れてく
the flowers wither away so fast.
愚鈍な僕は夢から覚めて
Foolish me, waking up from the dream,
綴った意味も無い無い無いな
with no meaning left at all...
不毛な日々を丁寧に
Carefully tending to barren days,
綴った紙に花を描いた
I drew flowers on the woven paper.
不遇な僕らは夢に敗れて
Unfortunate, defeated by our dreams,
誓った筈も無かった事にした
we pretended the vows we made never happened.
Daphne, Ficus, Iris, Maackia, Lythrum, Myrica, Sabia,
Thymus, Ribes, Abelia, Sedum, Felicia, Ochna, Lychnis, flos.
ずっと夢見てた僕になれたかな
I wonder if I've become the me I always dreamed of.
とうに帰れないとこまで来たみたい
It feels like I've gone past the point of no return.
自分の足で二段飛ばして もっと先へ駆けでいけるはずだから ran away
I should be able to run even further ahead on my own two feet, so ran away—
深くなる傷を縫い付け
Stitching together the deepening wounds,
繋ぐパス軸に回り出す
spinning around the connecting pathways.
慣れた痛み 焦る呼吸とビート
Familiar pain, hurried breathing, and beats,
気付かないふりしてまた一人
pretending not to notice, once again alone.
何が正当？ ないな永劫
What is right? There is no eternity.
誰が間違った 対価払うの
Who was wrong, and who pays the price?
あなたが嫌いなあいつはきっと
That person you hate so much
ただ「それだけ」で不正解なんだ
is simply considered wrong just for that reason.
零点だって提言したって全然納得できない理由も
Even when declared a zero, the reasons make no sense at all.
最前線はいつだってここだった 最善策は最初からなかった
The front line was always right here; there was no best plan from the start.
緩やかに崩れ壊れてく
Slowly and gently, it crumbles and breaks,
ゆりゆり首を締めるように 昨日までの僕が
as if gently choking the me of yesterday.
殺されてゆく 緩やかに
Gradually being killed off,
離れ離れ 遠ざかるよ
drifting further and further apart.
ぐるりるり 君に聴こえるのは
What you hear, Grrr-ruri,
僕が知らない声になってく
becomes a voice I don't know.
幼い頃から 気付いたら傍にいた
Since I was little, before I knew it, you were by my side.
まるで空気のようだ
Like air itself,
僕は君とぎゅっと手を繋いで
I held your hand tightly.
楽しいことも涙も 僕は君に話して聴かせた
I shared all my fun times and tears with you.
僕を笑う人や非難する声が聴こえるように君は歌った
You sang so I could hear people laughing at or condemning me.
この声を君が受信 また夜毎投影されてく
Receiving this voice, projected every night,
使い捨てだって言って腐っても止まらないハイファイタイトガイ
a high-fi tight guy who never stops even if called disposable and rotten.
一周巡る間の たった一瞬だけでも
Even if it's just for a fleeting moment as we go full circle,
交わる鼓動、音、繋ぐ色 次は僕が君に歌うんだから
our beating hearts and sounds intertwine—next, I will sing to you.
緩やかに 離れ離れ 崩れ壊れてく
Gradually, crumbling and breaking apart...
ゆるりゆるり首を締めるように 昨日までの僕が殺されていく
Like tightening a noose, yesterday's me is being killed off.
緩やかに 離れ離れ 遠ざかるよ
Gradually drifting further and further apart.
ぐるりるり 君に聴こえるのは 僕が知らない声になってく
What you hear, Grrr-ruri, becomes a voice I don't know.
緩やかに 崩れ壊れてく
Gradually crumbling and breaking apart...
ゆるりゆるり首を締めるように 昨日までの僕が殺されていく
Like tightening a noose, yesterday's me is being killed off.
緩やかに 離れ離れ 遠ざかるよ
Gradually drifting further and further apart.
ぐるりるり 君に聴こえるのは 僕が知らない声になってく
What you hear, Grrr-ruri, becomes a voice I don't know.
いつか君に届くかな いやそんな日はきっと来ないだろうな
Will it ever reach you? No, a day like that will never come.
声も身体も持たぬ君に 救われたな 何億人のひとり
Saved by you who had neither voice nor body.
赤青合わせ彩った 音で世界が溢れた
The world overflowed with sounds colored by red and blue.
巡り巡り出会ったこの音を聴く すべてが
Listening to this sound we met, everything...
緩やかに 崩れ壊れてく
Gradually crumbling and breaking apart...
ゆるりゆるり首を締めるように 昨日までの僕が殺されていく
Like tightening a noose, yesterday's me is being killed off.
緩やかに 離れ離れ 遠ざかるよ
Gradually drifting further and further apart.
ぐるりるり 君に聴こえるのは 僕が知らない声になってく
What you hear, Grrr-ruri, becomes a voice I don't know.
緩やかに 崩れ壊れてく
Gradually crumbling and breaking apart...
ゆるりゆるり首を締めるように 昨日までの僕が殺されていく
Like tightening a noose, yesterday's me is being killed off.
緩やかに 離れ離れ 遠ざかるよ
Gradually drifting further and further apart.
ぐるりるり 君に聴こえるのは 僕が知らない声になってく
What you hear, Grrr-ruri, becomes a voice I don't know.
はあ、お歌い改めて、おめでとう！
Phew! Okayu, once again, happy birthday!
ありがとう、ころさん。
Thank you, Korosan.
なんか、この曲一緒に歌いたいって言ってもらえてすごいね、嬉しかった。
I was so happy when you told me you wanted to sing this song together.
そう、なんか、この歌の歌詞がね、歌詞の中にこう、すごく僕がころさんに対して思ってるなっていうこととか、
Yeah, the lyrics of this song... I feel like they express so much of what I think about Korosan,
ころさんが僕に対してこんなふうに思ってくれてたら嬉しいなっていうことが、なんかたくさん詰まってるなって思ったから、
and I thought it would make me so happy if Korosan felt that way about me too, so those feelings were packed in there.
これをね、自分の誕生日に一緒に歌いたかったんだ。
That's why I wanted to sing this together on my birthday.
嬉しい。
I'm so happy.
あのね、唐突だけどね、今日お便りが返ってきたの。
Um, all of a sudden, but today a letter came back!
え！？ちょっと、読ませていただきます。
Eh?! Wait, let me read it.
うん。
Yeah.
ええ、いきます。おかゆへ。
Um, here we go. To Okayu:
おかゆ、お誕生日おめでとう。おかゆはいつもコーネをたくさん褒めてくれるけど、今日はコーネがおかゆを褒めたいと思います。
Okayu, happy birthday. You always praise Korone a lot, so today Korone wants to praise Okayu.
おかゆは本当に歌が上手です。艶があって色気があってずっと聴いていたい歌声です。
Okayu, you're really good at singing. Your voice has gloss and allure, a voice I want to listen to forever.
おかゆは本当に優しいです。
Okayu, you're truly kind.
コーネが悲しい時自分のことのように悲しんでくれるし、
When Korone is sad, you grieve as if it were your own,
コーネが傷ついた時ギュッとして慰めてくれます。
and when Korone gets hurt, you hold her tight and comfort her.
おかゆは本当に面白いです。おかゆが喋ったことでたくさん腹筋が割れたよ。
Okayu, you're really funny. Because of things you've said, my abs have split from laughing so much!
どこでもどこでもコーネを支えてくれるおかゆ。コーネもずっとずっとそんなおかゆを支えていきます。
Okayu, who supports Korone anywhere and everywhere. Korone will keep supporting Okayu forever and ever too.
生まれてきてくれてありがとう。コーネより。
Thank you for being born. From Korone.
コーさん！
Korosan!
おめでとう！おめでとうね！
Congratulations! Happy birthday!
めちゃ嬉しい。え、そのお手紙さ、記念に持って帰ってもいい？
I'm so happy. Um, can I take that letter home as a memento?
や、あの、あとでちょっとせーしょ、あの、違う、ちゃんと書きからこれわ。
No, um, I'll make a clean copy later—well no, I'll write it properly, this is...
いいよ、いいよ、そのまま！
It's fine, just as it is!
いや違うの！ちゃんと書くから！
No wait! I'll write it properly!
これさ...
This...
の裏じゃねえかよお！
That's the back, isn't it?!
どうか行き上がったあ！
How did you get up there?!
まあなんか、しょうがない1人になったからね、この後のことでも話そうかな。
Well, since I'm all alone now, I guess I'll talk about what's next.
この後は、僕の2個目の新しいオリジナル曲のお披露目になるから、聞いてってよね！
After this will be the debut of my second new original song, so be sure to listen!
そこにいるころさんも、みんなも！
Corone right over there, and everyone else too!
では、聞いてください、新しい僕のオリジナル曲、「デタバレネコ」！
So please listen to my new original song, "Detabare Neko"!
酸いも甘いも全部かもあれで　シリアスな苦みに捲らう
Whether sweet or sour, wrap it in serious bitterness.
気付けばなにも選べなくなって
Before I knew it, I couldn't choose anything anymore.
僕らは大人になったんだ　被害者ヅラは誓ったか
We've become adults. Did you swear to wear a victim's face?
取り戻そうよダッカンだ
Let's take it back and reclaim it!
右見て　左見て　3回回ってにゃにゃにゃ
Look right, look left, spin three times, nyanyanya.
全部自分で選んできた　全部自分で決めたんだ
I chose everything by myself, I decided everything myself.
後付けだけどね乗り気っと
It's a post-hoc excuse, but I'm into it.
ああ　僕は世界の誰からも愛される存在にはなれなかったけど
Ah, I couldn't become someone loved by anyone in the world, but
何者にもなれなかったけど　君のとなで笑っていたかったなあ
Though I couldn't become anyone special, I wanted to laugh by your side.
デタラメな気持ちを歌にのせるよ
I'll put these nonsensical feelings into a song.
ネタバレはやめてよね
Stop giving away spoilers, okay?
いやでもちょっとだけなら　まあまあ妄想もタケナワさようなら
Well, if it's just a little bit... my delusions are at their peak, farewell.
右見て　左見て　3回回ってもうやめた
Look right, look left, spin three times, I quit already.
優しい君が側にいてくれてよかった
I'm glad gentle you were by my side.
厳しい君が側にいてくれてよかった
I'm glad strict you were by my side.
どうでもいい君も側にいてくれてよかった
I'm glad indifferent you were also by my side.
やっぱり嘘　どうでもいい　なんて嘘
Turns out it's a lie, I don't care, what a lie.
ああ　僕は世界のどこかでこのままでさ　存在していいんだってことを感じさせてくれたのは
Ah, what made me feel that it's okay to just exist somewhere in this world...
君のそんな言葉だった気がするから
...was words like that from you, or so I feel.
ああ　僕は世界の誰からも愛される存在にはなれなかったけど
Ah, I couldn't become someone loved by anyone in the world, but
何者にもなれなかったけど　君のとなで笑っていたかったなあ
Though I couldn't become anyone special, I wanted to laugh by your side.
デタラメな気持ちを歌にのせるよ
I'll put these nonsensical feelings into a song.
ネタバレはやめてよね
Stop giving away spoilers, okay?
いやでもちょっとだけなら　まあまあ妄想もタケナワさようなら
Well, if it's just a little bit... my delusions are at their peak, farewell.
ああ、まだ帰っちゃだめ！
Ah, don't go home yet!
もう少しだけ僕に付き合ってね。
Keep me company for just a little longer, okay?
猫又おかゆ誕生日記念グッズ2022発売します！イエーイ、やったあ！
Nekomata Okayu's 2022 Birthday Commemorative Goods are now on sale! Yay, hooray!
グッズの紹介をしていくね。
I'll introduce the goods.
初めに紹介するのはこちら、B2タペストリーだよ！
First up is this, the B2 tapestry!
こちら、僕のママである神岡ちろる先生に描き下ろししてもらったよ、かわいい！
This was newly drawn by my mama, Kamioka Chiroru-sensei. So cute!
今年はでっかく、いろんなことに挑戦したいという思いを込めて、宇宙スタイルとなっております！
This year, filled with the desire to bravely challenge all sorts of things, it has a space style!
2つ目、アクリルスタンド＆お茶碗！
Second, Acrylic Stand & Rice Bowl!
こちらは大好きななもり先生に描き下ろしをしていただきました！
This was newly illustrated by my beloved Namori-sensei!
このグッズはアクリルスタンドの僕が持っているお茶碗が実際に お茶碗としても販売するという、ご飯を食べている時に近くにアクリルスタンドがあると、一緒にご飯を食べているような気持ちになれるグッズだよ！
This item is sold as an actual rice bowl matching the one held by the acrylic stand. Having the acrylic stand nearby makes you feel like you're eating together!
ちなみにアクリルスタンドの台座はザブトンとなっております、かわいい！
By the way, the base of the acrylic stand is a zabuton cushion, so cute!
3つ目ははらまき！
Third is the haramaki belly warmer!
このグッズは僕が描いたイラストがはらまきになったよ、かわいい！
This item features an illustration drawn by me turned into a haramaki, so cute!
後ろを向くと尻尾もついていて猫気分を味わえます、ふふっ。
When you turn around, it has a tail attached so you can feel like a cat, hehe.
こころも
Your heart
おなかも
and your tummy,
ぼくがぜんぶ守ってあげるからね！
I'll protect them both completely!
最後はボイスセットの販売です。
Finally, we have the voice sets.
ガチ恋向けシチュエーションボイス4種、
4 types of devoted romance situation voices,
ショートシチュエーションボイス4種、
4 short situation voices,
不思議シチュエーションボイス4種、
4 mysterious situation voices,
ショートボイス10種となっております。
and 10 short voices.
ぼくは毎月ASMRをやってるんだけど、
I do ASMR every month, but
また一味違ったぼくが楽しめること、間違いなしです！
there's no doubt you'll enjoy a different side of me!
あ、そうそう！
Ah, that's right!
ASMRでおもい出した。
That reminds me of ASMR.
今回は誕生日記念フルセット購入特典として、
As a special purchase bonus for the full birthday set,
直筆サイン入りポストカードと特典ASMRボイスがついてくるよ。
you get a hand-signed postcard and bonus ASMR voice.
あ、直筆サイン入りポストカードと聞いて慌てているそこの君！
Ah, you there, panicking at the mention of a hand-signed postcard!
大丈夫だよ！
It's okay!
今回個数制限はないから、
There's no quantity limit this time,
フルセット購入してくれる人全員にサインが届くよ。
so everyone who buys the full set will get a signature.
楽しみにしててね！
Look forward to it!
だいたいそんな感じ。
That about sums it up.
今日はたくさんの思い出をみんなと作れて本当うれしかった。
I was so happy to make so many memories with everyone today.
ありがとうね！
Thank you!
みんなのこと大好きだよ！
I love you all so much!
チュー
Mwah!
ではでは、感触おかゆー！
Well then, feeling Okayu!